Hello everyone, I am Yuan Yuan
大家好,我是圓圓
I want to tell everyone
我要跟大家說一下
I have decided to come and live in Taitung.
我決定要來住台東
Actually, I am really very happy
其實我真的非常的開心
because I have been living in Taiwan for quite a long time
因為我已經住在台灣蠻久
but I found
但我發現
some things in Taiwan
還有一些台灣的事情
we need to be very clear
我們要非常的清楚
For example, now is my first time
比如說現在是我第一次
stationed with a bicycle
駐有一台腳踏車
mobile
行動
if I were to come to Taitung before
我之前如果要來台東的話
I might rent a motorcycle
我可能會租一台機車
but now I feel
但是我現在覺得
I want to change, I want to experience
我要改變,我要體驗一下
a completely different thing
一個完全不一樣的事情
is
就是
riding bicycles, exploring Taitung
騎腳踏車,探險台東
really happy
真的好開心
Good, everyone let's go, I'll show you some places in Taitung.
好,大家我們出發,我給你看一些台東的地方
Good morning everyone
大家早安
live in Taitung
住在台東
How about waking up in the morning
早上起床怎麼樣
I will show you
我會給你看
my Airbnb provides breakfast
我的Airbnb提供早餐
So I have to go get breakfast
所以我要去拿早餐
my breakfast
我的早餐
then I think
那我覺得
I want to ride a bicycle to the beach
我要騎腳踏車去海邊
go to the beach for breakfast
去海邊吃早餐
good or not
好不好
Then I'll ride a bicycle to the beach now.
那我現在騎腳踏車去海邊
should take about one minute to ride
應該要騎一分鐘
very close
很近
saying good morning, enjoying the scenery, having breakfast
起床說好風景吃早餐
Wow
哇
Everyone eats breakfast here.
大家在這邊吃早餐
really amazing
真的很厲害喔
Is everyone too envious of me?
大家是不是太羨慕我了
okay
好啦
finished breakfast
吃完了早餐
almost about to go back to start working
差不多要回去開始工作
eight o'clock in the morning
現在早上八點
If living by the sea
我覺得住在海邊的話
really need to wake up a little earlier
真的要早一點起床
This way, there is a little time to enjoy
這樣還有一點時間可以享受
And if work
然後如果工作
smoothly
順利的話可能
5:30 p.m. can get off work
下午五點半可以下班
There is a little time to see the sunrise.
還有一點點時間可以看天亮
Welcome to
歡迎來到
Taitung lifestyle
台東的生活
Oh, by the way, I haven't shown everyone my room yet.
喔對了,我還沒給大家看我的房間
probably like this
大概是這樣
not big
沒有很大
my amazing bicycle
我的很厲害的腳踏車
is the most important tool of this trip
就是這趟旅行最重要的工具
then
然後
just like this, a bed
就是這樣子一個床
a small thing refrigerator television
一個小東西冰箱電視
toilet
廁所
Also, the most important thing is
還有最重要的就是
here
這邊
This is my studio.
這邊就是我的工作室
Look at how serious I am.
你看我這麼認真
I brought two screens.
我帶了兩個螢幕
It's my computer and also an extra monitor.
就是我的電腦還有就是額外螢幕
super convenient
超方便的
because it is small
因為它很小
can be put inside a bag
這樣可以放在包包裡面
about to start working
那差不多要開始工作
and hope to go
然後希望中午可以去
a nearby restaurant
某一家附近的餐廳
eat delicious food, see the sea
吃好吃的,看海
possible to play in the water
有可能會玩水嗎
oh yeah
喔耶
Noon time has come.
中午時間來了
Then I look at the nearby beach.
然後我看這個附近的沙灘
I decide to go for a swim
我決定要去游泳一下下
Alright, let's go.
好吧,我們出發
ah
啊
so comfortable
好舒服喔
super comfortable
超級舒服
and then need to check the surf conditions
然後要看浪況
Today the waves are not big, so I decided
今天浪不大,所以我就決定
To try
要試試看
Hmm, "耶" is a particle used to express excitement or surprise. A possible translation could be "Wow" or "Oh".
耶
I just played in the water
我剛剛玩水
and now I am going to have lunch
然後我現在要去吃午餐
I seemed to have not shown everyone
我好像沒有給大家看
my lunch how is it
我午餐怎麼樣
like this
就這樣
go to a cafe
去一個咖啡廳
and it also has air conditioning
然後它也有冷氣
I'm sorry, but "我今天去三明治" appears to be a mistake or unclear in its structure. It could either be a typo or a miscommunication. Can you please provide more context or clarify the sentence?
我今天去三明治
and mango smoothie
還有芒果冰沙
everyone, I'm off work
大家,我下班了
take a look
看一下
right after work
下班可以馬上
enjoy this scenery
享受這個風景
very happy
好開心喔
However, today's work is very hard.
不過今天工作很辛苦喔
working all day diligently
一整天真的在認真工作
in my own room in the morning
早上在我自己房間
Then in the afternoon working in the coffee shop
然後下午在咖啡廳工作
after work
但是下班
immediately come and enjoy
馬上可以來享受
such a beautiful scenery
這麼好的風景喔
Now wait a moment, it will get dark soon
現在等一下下會天黑
so I have to continue
所以我要繼續
enjoy this daytime period
享受這個白天時間
probably need to
晚上可能要
ride a bike to Taitung
騎車去台東吧
This scenery is really too beautiful.
這個風景真的太
beautiful, right
好看了吧
I rode a bicycle for 40 minutes.
我騎腳踏車40分鐘
arrived in Taitung City
就到了台東市
40 minutes is a bit long
40分鐘有點久
Round trip takes about one and a half hours
來回快一個半小時
I feel a little
我覺得我有點
underestimate this distance
小看這個距離
I thought Duran and Taitung City
我以為杜蘭跟台東市
in the middle is better
的中間去更好
But actually both sides are a bit too far away
但其實兩邊都有點太遠
come and have a look today
今天來看熱鬧一下
because these past few nights
因為這幾天晚上
very very quiet
非常非常的安靜
nothing
沒有什麼東西
I just bought a tofu pudding.
我剛剛買一個豆花
I just bought a tofu pudding to eat and completely forgot to take a picture for everyone to see.
吃然後完全忘了拍給大家看
I almost finished eating before I realized.
我快吃完才想到
Therefore, I took a picture of the last bite.
所以我拍那個最後一口
Why everyone knows why I ride a bike
大家知道為什麼我騎腳踏車
wearing these glasses, right?
戴這種眼鏡嗎
because there are many insects at night
是因為晚上很多蟲
I must protect my eyes
我一定要保護眼睛
far away eyes have touched many insects
遠遠的眼睛有碰過非常
many bugs
多的蟲
now be careful
現在要小心
This is the road I take on my way home
這個是我在回家的路
all black
全黑
Nothing much
沒有什麼東西喔
a little scary, but I have lights
有點可怕但是我都有燈
front light and rear light
前燈後燈
so I feel quite safe
所以我覺得蠻安心的
That may be because I have been waiting for the regular office workers in Taiwan.
那可能是因為我在台灣
have been waiting for office workers
一直等上班族
Monday to Friday fixed work
禮拜一到禮拜五固定要上班
So I think
所以我覺得
I must have missed some of my time in Taiwan
我在台灣一定有錯過一些
Taiwanese life
台灣生活的
experience
經驗嘛
but recently I decided to change
但是我最近決定我要改變了
actually, maybe everyone knows that I have been working from home for three years
其實可能大家知道我已經在家裡
work for three years
工作三年
Therefore, for these three years I have been thinking
所以這三年我一直在想
since working from home
那既然在家裡工作
Why are you still in Taipei?
為什麼還在台北呢
Then this time even if I won't
那這一次就算我不會
truly live in Taitung for a long term
真的長期住在台東
"But since I can use a computer"
但是既然我可以用電腦
work anywhere in Taiwan
在台灣任何一個地方工作
I decided to come and stay in Taitung for a while.
我決定要來住台東一段時間
Okay, I don't want to talk too much.
好啦我不要說太多話
because today is Sunday
因為今天去禮拜天
I don't have enough context to provide an accurate translation for the phrase "我不用上班." It could potentially mean "I don't need to go to work" or "I don't have to work."
我不用上班
so today I need a very very
所以我今天要一個非常非常
serious itinerary
認真的行程
I am now almost 100 kilometers.
我現在是快100公里
I want to go see many places in Taitung.
我要去看台東很多地方
So we need to depart first.
所以我們先要出發
and then chat with you later
然後晚一點跟你聊天
Then we arrived
那我們現在到了
a famous place near Dulan
獨蘭附近一個有名的地方
called Shui Wang upstream
叫做水王上流
It's the river on this side.
就是這邊的河流
because of its terrain
因為它的地形
a little bit special
有一點點特別
won't make people think that the water goes up
不會讓人以為水往上去
but of course, it's actually going down
但是當然其實是往下
right or correct
對不對
Therefore, the water goes this way
所以水是往這邊
to here
到這邊
and really feel
然後真的感覺到
a little upward
有點往上
we take a look
我們看一下喔
It really goes this way
它真的是往這邊
I made new friends.
我交了新的朋友
Hello everyone
哈囉大家好
you are walking around the island on foot
你是走路環島
walk
走路走路
Then you say today is the second day
然後你說今天第二天
yesterday, the first day from capital
昨天第一天從資本
to Fugang
到富岡
impressive
滿厲害的
You said that it's probably less than 30 kilometers a day.
你說一天大概有30公里以下
around 25 to 30
是25 30吧
don't want to walk so fast on this section
對這一段就說不想走那麼快
I said, "Let's walk slowly."
我說慢慢走
approximately within 30 kilometers per day
那大概每天預計在30公里以內
walk slowly
慢慢走
I want to ask why there is this plan
我想問一下為什麼有這個計畫
why or for what reason
有什麼原因還是為什麼
because it is a long-term plan
因為它是一個很久的計畫
maybe a month
有可能一個月
is
是
Sometimes staying in an environment for a long time
有時候在一個環境待久了
sometimes
就會
sometimes feel a little weary
有時候會有點倦怠
then
然後
walking actually in the process of hiking
走路其實在徒步的
during the process, actually, you will
過程當中其實你會
a long time alone
很長時間的一個人
Then you can calm down.
那你就可以冷靜下來
then think
然後想想
own life and own work
自己的生活想想自己的工作
and can fully
然後可以充分的
calm down one's heart
把自己的心靜下來
Walk with you peacefully
好好地跟你一起走
I think hiking for me
我覺得徒步對我來說
it is actually a journey of inner dialogue with oneself
它其實是一個與自己內心
journey of self-dialogue
對話的旅程
able to think about many things in this
在這之中能夠思考很多事
and think of many people
然後想很多人
let oneself be able to
讓自己能夠
recharge
充滿電
and then go back to and to
然後再回去兼對
arduous work
艱苦的工作
I agree because I've been alone these past few days.
我同意因為我這幾天
also being alone
也是自己一個人
have a lot of time to think
有很多時間思考
Actually, I wanted to share with the audience
其實剛好我本來也想跟觀眾
share
分享說
even if we have many restrictions in our lives
就算我們生活很多的限制
Possibly have children possibly work
可能有小孩可能工作
very busy and under a lot of pressure
很忙壓力很大
but we can still
但是我們還是可以
If we can change a little bit
我們如果可以改變一下
our way of life
我們生活的方式
can be happier like this
可以這樣更快樂
like me deciding to stay here for a week
像我現在決定要住這邊一個禮拜
through different environments
就透過不一樣的環境
and then challenging oneself
然後刺激自己
to challenge oneself
對挑戰自己
yes, great
對啊很棒
then I wish you
那我祝你
smoothly
順利
Wishing you a smooth welcome to Taiwan
祝你順利歡迎你來台灣
thank you
謝謝你謝謝
I arrived at a place
好我到了一個地方
called Taiyuan Yougu
叫做太原幼谷
This is in Donghe District.
這個是在東河
is the
東河就是
First, there is Taitung, and then there is Dulan further up, and then Donghe.
先有台東然後往上有獨蘭
Then go to Donghe
再來東河
I heard this place is very beautiful and there will be monkeys.
我聽說這邊很美然後會有猴子
so I came to take a look
所以我來看看
take a look at what kind of scenery
看一下有什麼樣的風景
this place has really many monkeys
這個地方真的很多的猴子
I see the photos of Google Maps.
我看Google地圖的照片
I see a lot of people coming here
我看到很多來這邊
really right
真的是沒錯
a little scary
有一點點可怕
because someone is feeding monkeys
因為有人餵猴子
seems like not possible
好像不行
because they will become more and more accustomed
因為他們會越來越習慣
But everyone still thinks it's fun
但是大家還是覺得很好玩
so they will still feed them
所以還會餵他們
feel that they won't attack people
感覺他們沒有會攻擊人
but I usually don't get so close to them
但我通常不會那麼靠近他們
because I had been threatened before
因為我之前
threatened
被威脅
I feel scared
我覺得很可怕
so now I keep my distance
所以我現在比較保持距離
I want to say
我想說
success
成功
Wow, I'm currently at Taitung's beach.
哇我現在在
Taitung beach
台東的海邊
awesome
好棒喔
I was just in a café.
我剛剛在一個咖啡廳
on top
在上面
and the scenery of this café
然後這個咖啡廳的風景
awesome
超級棒
can see the sea and enjoy
可以在那邊看海享受
listen to what hammocks
聽到什麼吊床嗎
I see everyone really relaxing here
我看大家在這邊真的很放鬆
enjoying the view of the sea
在那邊看海享受
Do you hear any hammocks
聽到什麼吊床嗎
enjoying the view of the sea there
在那邊看海享受
wow
哇
everyone look
大家看一下
Taitung Beach
台東的海邊
awesome
超棒的
very natural
非常的自然
Now only I am alone, oh
現在只有我自己一個人喔
all belong to me
全部都是我的
very different from Taipei
跟台北差很多
different from Taipei
Different from Taipei (or Taipei is very different)
跟台北差很多
different from Taipei
different from Taipei by a lot
跟台北差很多
Wow
哇
I went to many places today.
我今天去很多地方
the sun is big and not easy
太陽很大不簡單
but I am very very
但是我非常非常的
satisfied
滿足
because I feel that actually Taiwan
因為我覺得其實台灣
not only one
不只有一個
many Taiwans
有很多個台灣
And what each of us sees of Taiwan
然後我們每一個人看到的台灣
is one aspect of Taiwan
就是其中一個台灣的方面
I have been a Taipei office worker for these years.
我這幾年都是台北上班族
the Taiwan I see
所以我看到的台灣
it is this Taiwan
就是這個台灣
likely the majority in Taipei
可能是大部分在台北
sometimes go to other places
偶爾會去別的地方
play, travel
玩啊旅行
but I have always hoped for the opportunity
但是我一直希望有機會
live a different life
住別的生活
in Taitung here
在這邊台東
or live in Kenting
還是住在墾丁
live in many places
住在很多地方
then I hope to have this opportunity this year
然後我希望今年有這種機會
I hope I can do it often
我希望我可以常常做
this kind of experience
這種體驗
This time in Taitung
這一次在台東
happy
很開心
I am now going to buy dinner
我現在要去買晚餐
I want to go to Duran to buy dinner
我要去杜蘭買晚餐
because there are no restaurants where I live
因為我住的地方沒有餐廳了
everyone take a look at this amazing scenery
大家看一下這個風景
super awesome
超級棒喔
thinking about these days
對我這幾天都在想
actually why do some people feel
其實為什麼有人會覺得
Taiwan is great
台灣很棒
that some people would actually find life
那有人會覺得其實生活
very boring and not very enjoyable
很無聊啊沒有很喜歡
I think it's all because
我覺得都是因為
our way of life
我們生活的方式
some things we can change
有一些我們可以改變
our lives
讓我們的生活
more interesting
更有趣
This week, my purpose is to accomplish this.
那我這個禮拜就是這個目的
I decided to leave Taipei.
我決定要離開台北
experience
體驗一下
Taitung's life
台東的生活
every day is a very
每一天都是一個非常
fresh experience
新鮮的體驗
then I wonder why
然後我覺得為什麼
Durand, many Taiwanese people
杜蘭很多台灣人
and many foreigners
還有很多外國人
decide to settle there
決定要定住那邊
because everyone likes different things
就是因為大家都喜歡
different lifestyle
不一樣的生活
I'm sorry, but "那杜蘭" seems to be a name or a place that I am not familiar with. It is not possible to provide a translation without more context or information.
那杜蘭真的是不一樣
different, not drop, really different, very easy
不掉真的不一樣很輕鬆
everyone has the opportunity to truly
大家有機會可以真的
leave everything
離開一切
one week, two weeks, three weeks
一個禮拜兩個禮拜三個禮拜
come and experience
來體驗一下
I think Taiwan is actually
我覺得台灣原來
so great
這麼棒
OK everyone today
OK大家今天
go to the last day
去最後一天
I will return to Taipei in the afternoon.
我下午要回台北
I have already checked out, my backpack is overweight.
我已經check out我的背包超重
I'm almost going
我差不多要去
go to Taitung and then take the train back to Taipei
台東去然後坐火車
go back to Taipei
回台北
This seven days passed very quickly
這個七天過得非常快
I'm a bit reluctant to leave here now.
我現在有點捨不得離開這邊
I think
我覺得
within seven days
我在七天內
especially cycling
尤其是騎腳踏車
Taitung Line
台東線
I discovered another Taiwan.
我發現另外一個台灣
really is another Taiwan
真的是另外一個台灣
including my Taiwan in Taipei is completely different
連我在台北的台灣是完全不一樣
So I feel that this time I stayed for seven days
所以我覺得這一次我待了七天
but in the future, I will really stay longer
但我以後真的會待比較久
possibly stay for a month
可能會待一個月
still possibly moving here
還是可能會搬到這裡
I really want to seize this opportunity
我真的想抓這個機會
get to know more about the Taitung Line
認識台東線更多
This place is great, I am now starting to understand the people in Taiwan.
這邊非常棒我現在開始
understand Taiwanese people
了解台灣人
still foreigner deciding to live in
還是外國人決定要住在
because of here
這裡因為
The translation of "這裡生活不一樣" is "life here is different".
這裡生活不一樣
and your life
然後你生活的
excellent quality
品質很棒
just after you finish work
就是你下班
immediately in a great place
馬上在一個很棒
very comfortable and peaceful place
很舒服很安靜的地方
no air pollution
沒有空氣污染
not many
沒有很多
our troubles in the big city
我們在大城市的煩惱
hope everyone likes
好希望大家喜歡
this video
這個影片
and also please like, share, and subscribe
然後一樣請你按讚分享訂閱
And say goodbye to everyone next time
然後跟大家說下次見
everyone today is the last day
大家今天最後一天
almost about to leave
已經差不多要離開
from Taitung back to Taipei
台東回台北
I really can't bear to leave now.
我現在真的捨不得離開
because I feel seven days
因為我覺得七天
too short
太短
I feel very comfortable here.
我覺得在這邊太舒服
I now slowly begin to understand
我現在慢慢地開始了解
why so many people
為什麼這麼多人
want to live in Taitung
想住在台東
is another Taiwan
就是另外一個台灣
the Taiwan where I am in Taipei
跟我在台北的台灣
completely different
是完全不一樣
then I will definitely
那我以後一定
will have the opportunity to come back
會有機會回來
that everyone can leave a message to tell
那大家可以留言告訴
How do you feel about the Taitung Line?
我覺得台東線怎麼樣
And now I have to go back.
然後我現在要回去了
Goodbye everyone, please like, share, and subscribe. Goodbye.
大家掰掰請你按讚分享訂閱
goodbye
掰掰